## **Leo Edwards**

E-mail: leojpedwards@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/leo-edwards-5173aa127/

GitHub: https://github.com/LEO-E-100

Website: www.leo-edwards.co.uk Twitter: @leojpedwards

I am a London based data scientist, currently working on the Data Science Immersive course at General Assembly London.

After finishing my Master's I had a strong desire to delve deeper into data science and to really challenge myself to turn my hobby into a career.

At General Assembly I gained the experience and knowledge to approach data problems in a structured way to gain the most valuable insights.

I have a passion for combining my background in biology, computer science and data science. In particular in healthcare analytics which I feel is a vital and fascinating area of research to which I hope to contribute in the future.

## **Experience**

Sept 2017 - Present General Assembly - Data Science Immersive

GA Data Science Immersive (DSI) is a 12-week course in which students are trained in the fundamental techniques of Data Science. This covers data driven decision making and all industry standard tools of predictive analytics, data cleaning and data mining.

- Performing visualisation and statistical analysis of data using Pandas, NumPy and Matplotlib Python libraries
- Data Mining and Machine Learning using Scikit-Learn and StatsModels Random Forest, SVM, PCA, Logistic Regression, KNN, Clustering etc.
- Data extraction using Web Scraping, Scrapy and APIs
- Developed a Real Time events predictor employing a sophisticated web crawler, a variety of Machine Learning techniques to label and predict events as they occur. This involved a Big Data tools such as Spark to analyse such a large dataset

## **Education**

Sept 2016 - Sept 2017 University College London - MSc Computer Science

Completed a one year Master's level Degree in Computer Science. Particular emphasis was placed on Computational Biology and the analysis of Biological data. This course was designed to introduce the core concepts of Computer Science to students without a background in CS.

- Introductory Object Oriented Programming in Java
- Databases including SQL and NoSQL from a conceptual level through to the full implementation of a Social Network project
- App design taught through a real life project introduced through **Code4Health**
- Final dissertation project designed with the NHS

Oct 2013 - Jun 2016 University of Oxford - BA Biological Science

## **Employment**

Jun 2017 - Sept 2017 NHS integrated Web App **User Generated Outcomes** (UCL Project)

Designed and fully implemented a proof of concept web app for use by the NHS in tracking and storing patient history.

- Worked individually with oversight by an NHS Digital Consultant
- Key deliverables were produced to a high standard, well in excess of expectations and to unanimously positive feedback
- Key design features included: UI, data collection, data visualisation and database integration

Oct – Dec 2016 App designed for **Code4Health** (UCL Project)

Designed and implemented a cross-platform mobile app designed to improve patient understanding of blood tests and to raise the levels of result retrieval amongst NHS patients.

- Key areas of design included: UI, data collection and information delivery
- Worked in a team of three to carry out the full process of design and implementation
- App completed on time and received positive feedback